<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Programming on Charlie Hulcher</title><link>https://charlie.engineer/tags/programming/</link><description>Recent content in Programming on Charlie Hulcher</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright> 2025 Charlie Hulcher</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><ttl>60</ttl><atom:link href="https://charlie.engineer/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Coding is Creative</title><link>https://charlie.engineer/posts/coding-is-creative/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://charlie.engineer/posts/coding-is-creative/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When you think about programming (or coding), you might not consider it to be a creative pursuit. That’s a viewpoint that I, as a coder, was very confused by, because I see it as one of the better avenues for creativity available today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this piece changes the way you think about programming and encourages further exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programming as a creative outlet can be understood by comparing it to traditional artistic pursuit.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>programming,thought</category></item><item><title>Grand Prize at LA Hacks - Virtual Reality Treadmill</title><link>https://charlie.engineer/posts/la-hacks-tred/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 08:27:58 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://charlie.engineer/posts/la-hacks-tred/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We won the &lt;a href="https://www.laweekly.com/ucla-hosts-biggest-hackathon-in-history/"&gt;&amp;ldquo;largest hackathon in history&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;: the Grand Prize at LA Hacks. Built over 36 hours with our team of three, our treadmill captures user movement and translates it into motion in any virtual reality world. It was designed to be low-cost, widely compatible, and high-performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the user moves across the surface of the treadmill, low cost sensors activate from pressure, and an Arduino clusters the inputs to interpret the user&amp;rsquo;s motion (direction and intent - standing, walking, running). Those clusters are sent as keyboard button presses to the computer running the virtual reality world. The user wears an Oculus Rift.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>programming,competition,arduino</category></item><item><title>Autonomous Hovercraft</title><link>https://charlie.engineer/posts/autonomous-hovercraft/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 08:50:26 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://charlie.engineer/posts/autonomous-hovercraft/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We won the University of Maryland Clark School of Engineering semester-long freshman competition, which puts all freshman engineering students into teams to navigate a course and retrieve a payload by building an autonomous hovercraft. I led our team of ten, and focused on circuitry and programming. From mechanical design, circuitry, and autonomous sensing, navigation, and actuation, our hovercraft was the fastest and completed the most objectives.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>programming,arduino,competition</category></item></channel></rss>